Doris McLoughlin Collection of Textile Related Photographs 6610 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Doris McLoughlin Collection of Textile Related Photographs
1936
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Doris McLoughlin
6610 P
1 folders
1 file folder.
Gelatin silver print, photographs.
Images of the flooding in March, 1936, in both Andover and Lawrence, Massachusetts.
10062117
Scope and Contents
Includes six images of Shawsheen Village in Andover, Massachusetts, and five images the Merrimack River in Lawrence, Massachusetts.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives 227 Ives Hall Tower Road Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheelref@cornell.edu https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/
Compiled by:
R. Miles, October 05, 2017
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, November 14, 2017
Floods; Floods -- Massachusetts -- Andover; Textile factories -- Massachusetts -- Andover; Andover (Mass.); Lawrence (Mass.); Merrimack River (N.H. and Mass.); Shawsheen Village (Mass.); American Woolen Company; Wood Worsted Mill (Lawrence, Mass.)
10062117
- Photographs of the Flood of 1936 in Andover and Lawrence, Massachusetts (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Shawsheen Village, Andover, Massachusetts, 1936; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts the American Woolen Company buildings in the background during the flood of 1936. Floodwaters are difficult to see, but buildings are reflected in waters. Onlookers move towards the background to view the water. Cars parked on the street leading to the water. 12 x 7 cm.
    Format: black and white photograph.
  - Item 2: Shawsheen Village, Andover, Massachusetts, 1936; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts Shawsheen Village houses during the flood of 1936. Note the cars parked on the street on the left, one of which has driven to the edge of the water. Floodwaters appear more severe on the right. Taken from a high angle, possibly from the American Woolen Company buildings (?). See also items 3 through 6 for views from this angle of the flood. 12.5 x 7 cm.
  - Item 3: Shawsheen Village, Andover, Massachusetts, 1936; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts Shawsheen Village houses during the flood of 1936. View is from a different angle than item 2. Taken from a high angle, possibly from the American Woolen Company buildings (?). See also item 2 and items 4 through 6 for views from this angle of the flood. 12.75 x 7 cm.
  - Item 4: Shawsheen Village, Andover, Massachusetts, 1936; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts Shawsheen Village houses during the flood of 1936. From this angle, houses in the foreground have not been touched by the floodwaters, but the houses seen across the river have water close to the first floor level. Taken from a high angle, possibly from the American Woolen Company buildings (?). See also items 2 through 3 and items 5 through 6 for views from this angle of the flood. 12.5 x 7 cm.
  - Item 5: Mill buildings in Shawsheen Village, Andover, Massachusetts, 1936; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts some of the mill buildings in Shawsheen Village affected by the flood of 1936. Water has reached the first floor of the building on the left as well as the building in the center right. The front of the houses in the foreground is still dry, but water is very close to the back. See item 6 for a slightly different angle on this view. Taken from a high angle, possibly from the American Woolen Company buildings (?). See also items 2 through 4 and item 6 for views from this angle of the flood. 12.5 x 7 cm.
  - Item 6: Mill buildings in Shawsheen Village, Andover, Massachusetts, 1936; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts some of the mill buildings in Shawsheen Village affected by the flood of 1936. Water has reached the first floor of the building in the center left, as well as other commercial buildings in the photo. See item 5 for a slightly different angle on this view. Taken from a high angle, possibly from the American Woolen Company buildings (?). See also items 2 through 5 for views from this angle of the flood. 10.5 x 7 cm.
  - Item 7: Merrimack River in Lawrence, Massachusetts, 1936; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts a view of the Merrimack River in Lawrence, Mass., during the flood of 1936. A number of houses appear to be partially underwater in the background; some appear flooded up to the top of the first-story windows. A small rowboat with two figures in it is in the center background. See also item 8 through 10 for views of the Merrimack in the Lawrence area during the flood. 10.25 x 6 cm.
  - Item 8: Merrimack River in Lawrence, Massachusetts, 1936; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts a view of the Merrimack River in Lawrence, Mass., during the flood of 1936, showing two houses in the center and left background that appear to be almost totally underwater. See also item 7, item 9, and item 10 for views of the Merrimack in the Lawrence area during the flood. 10.25 x 6 cm.
  - Item 9: A view of the Merrimack River in Lawrence, Massachusetts, 1936; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts a view of the Merrimack River in Lawrence, Mass., during the flood of 1936. See also item 7, item 8, and item 10 for views of the Merrimack in the Lawrence area during the flood. 10.25 x 6 cm.
  - Item 10: Mills along the Merrimack River in Lawrence, Massachusetts, 1936; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts a view of a number of mills along the Merrimack River in Lawrence, Mass., during the flood of 1936. Floodwaters have reached at least to the first floor of the buildings. See also items 7 through 9 for views of the Merrimack in the Lawrence area during the flood. 10.25 x 6 cm.
  - Item 11: Detail of Wood Mill, Lawrence, Massachusetts, 1936; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin silver print snapshot. Image depicts a close-up view of part of the Wood Mill along the Merrimack River in Lawrence, Mass., during the flood of 1936. The floodwaters have reached at least to the first floor of the mill. 10.5 x 6 cm.